Guide to the Terry Sanford Papers, 1926-1996
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Legislative Files Series, 1986-1992
  - Foreign Relations Subseries, 1986-1992
    - General Files, 1987-1992
      - Persian Gulf War:
        - Op-Ed from national papers, 1990-1991 (Box 85)
        - Resolutions, 1990-1991 (Box 85)
        - Miscellaneous, 1990 (Box 85)
      - Republic of Azerbaijan, 1991 (Box 85)
      - Russia: Betsy Rollins, 1992 (Box 85)
      - Russia and American Scientific Exchange, 1992 (Box 85)
      - Russian Baseball Exchange: Phillip Ellen, 1991-1992 (Box 85)
      - Saudi Arabia: Scott Nelson, 1991-1992 (Box 85)
      - Soviet Union:
        - Crisis, 1991, (3 folders) (Box 85)
        - Eastern Europe, 1990, (2 folders) (Box 85)
        - Senate Delegation Trip report, 1987 (Box 85)
        - Treaty on Soviet Elimination of Intermediate Range and Shorter Range missiles, 1988, (2 folders) (Box 85)
        - Miscellaneous, 1989-1992 (Box 85)
      - Statements, 1987 (Box 85)
      - Subcommittee assignments: 102nd Congress, 1991 (Box 85)
      - Subcommittee on International Economic Policy, 1988 (Box 85)
      - Foreign Relations Trade, 1992 (Box 85)
      - Vance Gyrus: Testimony, 1991 (Box 85)
      - Weekly summaries, 1987 (Box 85)
      - USIA, 1991 (Box 85)
      - Yugoslavia:
        - 1991-1992 (Box 85)
        - Croatia, Serbia, etc., 1992 (Box 85)
      - Miscellaneous, 1992 (Box 85)
    - Nominations, 1986-1992
      Primarily consists of American Academy of Diplomacy submissions and Government Ethics Reports on nominees for ambassadorships and leadership positions of United States international agencies.
      Arranged alphabetically by country or agency.
      - 1991 (Box 86)
      - General, 1989, (2 folders) (Box 86)
      - Administration: Arthur W. Fort, 1989 (Box 86)
      - Agency for International Development (AID):
        - Brown, Reginald J., 1989 (Box 86)
        - Christenson, Philip L. 1989 (Box 86)
        - Randlett, Robert R., 1989 (Box 86)
      - Agency for International Development (AID):
        - Assistant Administrator for Science and Technology Richard E. Bissell, 1990 (Box 86)
        - External Affairs: C. Anson Franklin, 1990 (Box 86)
      - Argentina (Ambassador to): Terrence A. Todman, 1989 (Box 86)
      - Arms Control and Disarmament Agency:
        - Hamner, Stephen R. 1989 (Box 86)
        - Gordon, Bradley, 1990 (Box 86)
        - Koch, Susan, 1990 (Box 86)
        - Moodie, Michael L., 1990 (Box 86)
      - Bahrain: Hostler, Charles W. (Box 86)
      - Barbados (and Dominica, St. Lucia, St. Vincent, The Grenadines): Silverman, Joy A., 1989 (Box 86)
      - Benin: Isom, Harriet W. (Box 86)
      - Brazil: Melton, Richard, 1989 (Box 86)
      - Brunei: Phillips, Christopher H., 1989 (Box 86)
      - Burundi: Perry, Cynthia S., 1989 (Box 86)
      - Cameroon: Cook, Frances D., 1989 (Box 86)
      - Cape Verde: McNamara, Francis T., 1989 (Box 86)
      - Caribbean Basin Initiative: Taylor, Barrett, 1989 (Box 86)
      - Central African Republic: Simpson, Daniel H., 1989 (Box 86)
      - C.I.A.: Robert Gates, 1991 (Box 86)
      - CSBM (Confidence and Security Building Measures): Maresca, John J., 1990 (Box 86)
      - Consular Affairs: Tamposi, Elizabeth M., 1989 (Box 86)
      - CFE (Conventional Forces in Europe): Woolsey, R. James, 1989 (Box 86)
      - Cotê d'Ivoire: Brown, Kenneth L, 1989 (Box 86)
      - Counselor: Zoellick, Robert B., 1989 (Box 86)
      - Czechoslovakia: Black, Shirley Temple, 1989 (Box 86)
      - Defense and Space: Smith, David J., 1989 (Box 86)
      - Denmark: Brown, Keith Lapham, 1989 (Box 86)
      - Department of State: Zoellick, Robert B., 1989 (Box 86)
      - Disarmament: Ledogar, Stephen J., 1989 (Box 86)
      - Economic and Agricultural Affairs: McCormack, Richard T., 1989 (Box 86)
      - Fiji, Tonga, Tuvalu and Kiribati: Teegen, Evelyn Irene Hoopes, 1989 (Box 86)
      - Finland: Weinmann, John Giffen, 1989 (Box 86)
      - Foreign Service: Perkins, Edward J., 1989 (Box 86)
      - Gabon: Wauchope, Keith L, 1989 (Box 86)
      - Gambia: Washington, Ruth V., 1989 (Box 86)
      - Ghana: Ewing, Raymond C., 1989 (Box 86)
      - Greece: Sotirhos, Michael G., 1989 (Box 86)
      - Guatemala: Stoock, Thomas F., 1989 (Box 86)
      - Guinea- Bissau: Jacobsen, William L., 1989 (Box 86)
      - Haiti: Adams, Alvin P., 1989 (Box 86)
      - Holy See: Melady, Thomas P., 1989 (Box 86)
      - Honduras: Arcos, Cresencio, 1989 (Box 86)
      - Iceland: Cobb, Charles E., 1989 (Box 86)
      - India: Clark, William, 1989 (Box 86)
      - Inter-American Affairs: Aronson, Bernard, 1987-1989 (Box 86)
      - Inter-American Development Bank:
        - Angulo, Albert W., 1989 (Box 86)
        - Mellinger, Larry K., 1989-1990 (Box 86)
      - Inter-American Foundation, Administrator of AID and Member, Board of Directors: Roskens, Ronald W., 1990 (Box 86)
      - International Communications and Information Policy: Holmes, Bradley P., 1989 (Box 86)
      - International Monetary Fund (IMF): Dawson, Thomas C., 1989 (Box 86)
      - Ireland: Moore, Richard A., 1989 (Box 86)
      - Italy: Secchia, Peter F., 1989 (Box 86)
      - Jamaica: Holden, Glen A., 1989 (Box 86)
      - Japan: Armacost, Michael H., 1989 (Box 86)
      - Joint Commission/ U.S. and Canada:
        - Durnil, Gordon K., 1989 (Box 86)
        - Cleveland, Hilary P., 1989 (Box 86)
      - Kenya: Hempstone, Smith, 1989 (Box 86)
      - Legislature: Mullins, Janet G., 1989 (Box 86)
      - Luxembourg:
        - Bush, Frederick M., 1989 (Box 86)
        - Rowell, Edward M., 1990 (Box 86)
      - Malaysia: Cleveland, Paul M., 1989 (Box 86)
      - Malta: Novetzke, Sally J., 1989 (Box 86)
      - Mauritius: Korth, Penne Percy, 1989 (Box 86)
      - Mexico: Negroponte, John D., 1989 (Box 86)
      - Morocco: Ussery, Michael, 1989 (Box 86)
      - Multilateral Trade Negotiations: Lavorel, Warren A., 1989 (Box 86)
      - NATO: Taft, William H., 1989 (Box 86)
      - NATO burden sharing: Holmes, Henry Allen, 1989 (Box 86)
      - Nepal: Bloch, Julia Chang, 1989 (Box 86)
      - New Zealand; Samoa: Newman, Della M., 1989 (Box 86)
      - Nigeria: Walker, Lannon, 1989 (Box 86)
      - Norway: Ruppe, Loret Miler, 1989 (Box 86)
      - Office of Foreign Missions: Fields, David C., 1989-1990 (Box 86)
      - OAS:
        - Einaudi, Luigi R., 1989 (Box 86)
        - Keplinger, Henry F., 1989 (Box 86)
      - OPIC (Overseas Private Investment Corporation):
        - Barclay, H. Douglas, 1990 (Box 86)
        - Berg, James D., 1989 (Box 86)
        - Zeder, Fred M., 1989 (Box 86)
      - Papua New Guinea/ Solomon Islands/ Rep. of Vanuatu: Farrand, Robert W., 1989 (Box 86)
      - Peace Corps:
        - Coverdell, Paul D., 1989 (Box 86)
        - Zartman, Barbara, 1989 (Box 86)
      - People's Republic of China: Lilley, James R., 1989 (Box 87)
      - Peru: Quainton, Anthony C. and Ledogar, Stephen J., 1989 (Box 87)
      - Political Affairs: Kimmitt, Robert M., 1989 (Box 87)
      - Portugal: Briggs, Everett E., 1990 (Box 87)
      - Private Enterprise (Assistant Administrator for), Agency for International Development: Holsman, Henrietta H., 1990 (Box 87)
      - Property Issues: Salgo, Nicholas M., 1989 (Box 87)
      - Protocol: Reed, Joseph V., 1989 (Box 87)
      - Public Affairs: Tutwiler, Margaret, 1989 (Box 87)
      - Qator: Hambley, Mark G., 1989 (Box 87)
      - Romania: Green, Alan, 1989 (Box 87)
      - Saudia Arabia: Bookout, John F., 1992 (Box 87)
      - Sierra Leone: Young, Johnny, 1989 (Box 87)
      - South Africa: Swing, William L., 1989 (Box 87)
      - Sri Lanka and Maldives: Creedmore, Marion V., 1989 (Box 87)
      - START (Head of Delegation on Nuclear and Space Talks and Chief Negotiator on Strategic Nuclear Arms): Burt, Richard R., 1989 (Box 87)
      - Sudan: Cheek, James R., 1989 (Box 87)
      - Switzerland: Gildenhorn, Joseph B., 1989 (Box 87)
      - Tanzania: DeJarnette, Edmund, 1989 (Box 87)
      - Textile Matters: Sorini, Ronald J., 1989 (Box 87)
      - Textile Negotiation: Houston, William Henry: Nomination for Ambassador, 1987 (Box 87)
      - UAE (United Arab Emirates): Walker, Edward S., 1989 (Box 87)
      - United Kingdom Ambassador: Catto, Henry E. (Box 87)
      - United Nations:
        - Bailey, Pearl, 1989 (Box 87)
        - MacDougal, Gary E., 1989 (Box 87)
        - Pickering, Tom, 1989 (Box 87)
        - Watson, Alexander F. (Box 87)
      - US- USSR: Joseph, Robert G., 1989-1990 (Box 87)
      - USIA (United States Information Agency):
        - Gelb, Bruce S., 1989 (Box 87)
        - Kopp, Eugene P., 1989 (Box 87)
        - Glade, William P. (Educational and Cultural Affairs), 1989 (Box 87)
      - Venezuela: Javits, Eric M., 1989 (Box 87)
      - West Germany: Walters, Vernon A., 1989 (Box 87)
      - Zimbabwe: Rhodes, J. Stevem (Box 87)
      - Miscellaneous, 1990 (Box 87)
    - International Commission for Central America Recovery and Development, 1986-1992
      Includes committee and staff memoranda, legislation, correspondence, clippings, press releases, trip itineraries, and reports pertaining to Sanford's participation in the commission and to the broader Central American peace process.
      Dated files arranged chronologically. Others arranged alphabetically by subject.
      - 1986-1991, (10 folders) (Box 87)
      - Acceptances, 1986-1988 (Box 88)
      - Acosta de Fortin, Irma, 1991 (Box 88)
      - Advice to State, 1989, undated (Box 88)
      - Amendment to Dodd Bill, 1990 (Box 88)
      - Angel, Rafael, 1991 (Box 88)
      - Antigua Declaration, 1990, June (Box 88)
      - Arias, Oscar Sanchez, 1991 (Box 88)
      - Arias Foundation, 1991 (Box 88)
      - Arias: Peace Plan, 1987
        - North Carolina Press, 1987 (Box 88)
        - Speech/Resolution, 1987 (Box 88)
        - 10 Point Plan, 1987-1988 (Box 88)
      - Articles, 1986-1989 (Box 88)
      - Ascher, William, 1987-1990 (Box 88)
      - Bipartisan Accord on Central America, 1989, Mar.24 (Box 88)
      - Carnegie Corporation/ David Hamburg, 1987 (Box 88)
      - CA Agreements/Accords, 1987 (Box 88)
      - Bill with Aid Language, 1990 (Box 88)
      - Central American Bill with Aid Language, 1990 (Box 88)
      - Central American Democracy and Development Act S. 100 and Luncheon, 1991 (Box 88)
      - Central American Development Coordinating Commission (CADCC), 1989-1991, (4 folders) (Box 88)
      - Central America Meeting, 1990 (Box 88)
      - Central American Peace Accords, 1987-1990 (Box 88)
      - Central America Peace Plan:
        - 1987 (Box 88)
        - Hearings, 1987 (Box 88)
      - Central America Trade Commission, 1990-1991 (Box 88)
      - Central America Trips:
        - 1987-1991, (10 folders) (Box 88)
        - Clippings, 1991 (Box 88)
        - Nicaragua with VP for Chamorro inauguration, 1990 (Box 88)
        - Documents: (Box 89)
        - CADCC Declaration: Spanish/English, 1989 (Box 89)
        - CADCC Implementation: Spanish/English, 1989 (Box 89)
        - Foreign OPS Legislation, 1989 (Box 89)
      - Chile trip, 1991, Oct. (Box 89)
      - Clippings, 1991 (Box 89)
      - Codel Sanford:
        - 1987-1991, (8 folders) (Box 89)
        - Central America, 1987-1989, (2 folders) (Box 89)
        - Guatamala and Costa Rica, 1987 (Box 89)
      - Columbia, 1986 (Box 89)
      - Commission Report, 1989, (2 folders) (Box 89)
      - Commissioners, 1988 (Box 89)
      - Compact, 1989 (Box 89)
      - Compact Plan, 1989 (Box 89)
      - Concurrent Resolution:
        - 1987 (Box 89)
        - Dear Colleague letters, 1987 (Box 89)
        - Regional Economic Development, HR 4854, 1987 (Box 89)
      - Congressional Briefing Dinner, 1988, Aug.4 (Box 89)
      - Congressional Review Group for Commission, 1988 (Box 89)
      - Contra Aid:
        - Compromise, 1989 (Box 89)
        - Newspaper Column, 1987 (Box 89)
      - Correspondence, 1986-1990, (12 folders) (Box 90)
      - Costa Rica:
        - 1987-1990, (3 folders) (Box 90)
        - Commission meeting, 1987, (2 folders) (Box 90)
      - Cuba, 1988-1992 (Box 90)
      - Debates, dinners, meetings: Washington, DC, 1988, Nov.17-19 (Box 90)
      - Declaration of Antigua Accords, 1990 (Box 90)
      - Declaration of Central American Presidents, 1990 (Box 90)
      - Delgado, Pedro Abelardo, 1987 (Box 90)
      - Dinner: Central America and Senate, 1988, Aug. (Box 90)
      - Dinner invitations, 1988 (Box 90)
      - Duke:
        - Center for International Development New program, 1988 (Box 90)
        - Proposals to foundations, undated (Box 90)
        - Sept. 30 Status report, 1987 (Box 90)
        - An Economic Development Plan for Central America, 1987 (Box 90)
      - El Salvador: (Box 91)
        - 1987-1992, (5 folders) (Box 91)
        - Working group:
          - 1990, (2 folders) (Box 91)
          - Senate Democratic Conference, 1987-1990 (Box 91)
      - Enterprise for the Americas:
        - 1989-1992, (2 folders) (Box 91)
        - Hearing transcripts, 1990 (Box 91)
      - Fagan, Richard R.: Forging Peach/The Challenge of Central America, 1987, (2 folders) (Box 91)
      - Feinberg, Richard E.: Economic Assistance to Central America, 1987 (Box 91)
      - First meeting, 1987 (Box 91)
      - Floor statements:
        - 1987 (Box 91)
        - Arias Peace Plan and the Demise of the 2 Track Policy, 1987 (Box 91)
        - Central America and Nicaraguan Elections, 1990, Feb.28 (Box 91)
        - Costa Rican Peach Initiative, 1987, Feb.26 (Box 91)
        - Panama, 1990, Jan.24 (Box 91)
        - The Pursuit of Peace, 1987, Aug.5 (Box 91)
        - U.S. Foreign Policy for Central America, 1988, Aug. 1 (Box 91)
      - Ford Foundation, 1987 (Box 91)
      - Foreign Aid Bill, 1989 (Box 91)
      - Foreign Assistance, 1989 (Box 91)
      - Fundacion Centroamericana, undated (Box 91)
      - Funding: anddollar;155,000 additional, 1989 (Box 91)
      - Funding possibilities, 1989 (Box 91)
      - Guatemala, 1987-1992, (3 folders) (Box 91)
      - Habib memos, 1987 (Box 91)
      - Haiti, 1987-1992 (Box 91)
      - Hearing, 1987 (Box 91)
      - Hearing: Environmentally sustainable development in Central America, 1988 (Box 92)
      - Honduras, 1987-19992 3 folders) (Box 92)
      - Humanitarian Aid, 1988 (Box 92)
      - Humanitarian Assistance, 1988 (Box 92)
      - Information Congressional Review Group:
        - 1988, Mar.28 (Box 92)
        - Cover letters for report, 1989 (Box 92)
      - Initial meetings/organization, 1987 (Box 92)
      - INCAE (Instituto Centroamericano de Administracion de Empresas, 1990-1991 (Box 92)
      - Inter-American Dialogue: Johnson, Victor C., 1987-1989 (Box 92)
      - Interparliamentary Union (IPU):
        - 1989-1990 (Box 92)
        - Budapest conference, 1989 (Box 92)
        - London conference, 1989, (3 folders) (Box 92)
        - Uruguay, 1990 (Box 92)
      - Jamaica, 1987-1990 (Box 92)
      - W. K. Kellogg Foundation, 1984 (Box 92)
      - Legislation:
        - 1990 (Box 92)
        - Correspondence, 1991 (Box 92)
      - Letter to Congressmen and Senators, 1988, Mar.28 (Box 92)
      - Luncheon:
        - 1987, Nov.19 (Box 92)
        - 1988, June1 (Box 92)
      - Marshall Plan Bill, 1987-1990, (2 folders) (Box 92)
      - McCall, Dick: Sen. John F. Kerry's office, 1987 (Box 92)
      - Memorandums, 1987-1988, (2 folders) (Box 92)
      - Memorandums: Duke, 1987 (Box 93)
      - Mexican Plan: Robert Healy, 1989 (Box 93)
      - Mexico, 1987 (Box 93)
      - Mini Marshall Plan, 1990 (Box 93)
      - Names and addresses, 1987-1988 (Box 93)
      - NBC News Meet the Press, 1988, Jan.17 (Box 93)
      - Negotiations survey, 1981 (Box 93)
      - Nicaragua:
        - 1987-1992, (5 folders) (Box 93)
        - Pell and Pressler's Report trip, 1988 (Box 93)
      - Nicaraguan:
        - Constitution, 1987 (Box 93)
        - Elections, 1989-1990 (Box 93)
        - Resistance Assistance, 1988, undated (Box 93)
      - N.C. State Vet School: World Health Organization Center, undated (Box 93)
      - OAS Multinational Mission, 1988-1989 (Box 93)
      - Other names for International Commission, 1987-1988 (Box 93)
      - Panama, 1987-1990 (Box 93)
      - Panama Aid Package, 1990 (Box 93)
      - Pan American Health Organization (PAHO), 1988-1989 (Box 93)
      - Papers commissioned, 1983-1988 (Box 93)
      - Partners of the Americas, 1989 (Box 93)
      - Peace and Democracy Watch: Susan Kaufman Purcell, 1988 (Box 93)
      - Policy Retreat in Georgia: List of participants, undated (Box 93)
      - Press (essays and articles), 1986-1989, (2 folders) (Box 93)
      - Press packet, 1988-1990 (Box 93)
      - Press people, 1987-1989 (Box 93)
      - Public Affairs Research and Communications, Inc., 1988 (Box 93)
      - Puerto Rico, 1989 (Box 93)
      - Reagan's peace Plan, 1987 (Box 93)
      - Reagan's remarks to the Organization of American States, 1987, Oct.7. (Box 93)
      - Report and book from International Institute for Environment and Development, 1987 (Box 94)
      - Reports and press releases, 1986-1989 (Box 94)
      - Reports, drafts, 1989 (Box 94)
      - Reports on Economic Development, 1987-1988 (Box 94)
      - Report from meeting in Lejondals Castel, Bro, Sweden, 1988, June24-26 (Box 94)
      - Charles H. Revson Foundation: Eli Evans, 1987 (Box 94)
      - Robinson, James D.: A Comprehensive Agenda for LDC Debt and World Trade Growth, 1988 (Box 94)
      - S.Con.Res (Box 94)
      - S.100\S.3041\S.1274: Central American Democracy and Development Act:
        - 1987-1991:, (7 folders) (Box 94)
        - Commissioners/legislation with excerpts (Box 94)
        - Floor statements, 1990-1991 (Box 94)
        - Helms amendment, 1991 (Box 94)
        - Press releases, articles, 1990-1991 (Box 94)
        - Sanford statements, 1990 (Box 94)
      - S.1347: Senate Foreign Aid Authorization and other legislation, 1988-1989 (Box 94)
      - S.3041:
        - Defense, 1990, undated (Box 94)
        - Floor Statement and Testimony, 1990 (Box 94)
        - Hearing and Testimony, 1990 (Box 94)
        - Helms Amendment and Sanford substitute, 1990 (Box 94)
      - Sanford plan for Central America, 1987, undated, (2 folders) (Box 94)
      - San Jose speech, 1987 (Box 94)
      - Sasakawa Peace Foundation, 1987-1988 (Box 94)
      - Schoultz, Lars: Institute of Latin American Studies, UNC-Chapel Hill, 1987-1988 (Box 94)
      - Senate-Congressional Resolution 63, 1988-1991 (Box 94)
      - Senators Central America file for first day of 102nd Congress (Box 94)
      - Sklar, Berry: Senate Foreign Relations Commission, 1987 (Box 94)
      - Spanish speech, 1987 (Box 94)
      - Special Plan of Economic Cooperation for Central America, 1989-1990 (Box 94)
      - Speeches, 1989 (Box 94)
      - Statement before committee in support of S. Con. Res. 24 Costa Rica Peach Initiative, 1987 (Box 95)
      - Statements to Senate Floor, 1987, Feb.26 (Box 95)
      - Stockholm meeting, 1988 (Box 95)
      - Stockholm, Sweden, 1988, June23-27 (Box 95)
      - Study Task Force: Duke's Plan and Revisions, 1987, (2 folders) (Box 95)
      - Tinker Foundation, 1988 (Box 95)
      - United Nations, 1988 (Box 95)
      - USAID final report, 1989 (Box 95)
      - U.S. government scholarships benefiting CBI countries, 1987-1988 (Box 95)
      - Who's Who names and numbers, 1987-1988 (Box 95)
      - Miscellaneous, 1990, undated, (2 folders) (Box 95)
    - Subcommittee on Near Eastern and South Asian Affairs, 1987-1992
      Correspondence, memoranda, reports, legislation, international agreements, maps, statements, and clippings from this subcommittee, which Sanford chaired. Subject covered include the Persian Gulf War and United States relations with Israel, Egypt, Iraq, Iran, and other nations in the Middle East.
      Files are arranged alphabetically by subject
      - Afghanistan/ Pakistan, 1988 (Box 95)
      - Algeria, 1990-1992 (Box 95)
      - Arms control, 1991 (Box 95)
      - Bangladesh, 1988-1992 (Box 95)
      - China:
        - MFN, 1987-1990, (13 folders) (Box 95)
        - Students, 1989-1990, (2 folders) (Box 95)
      - Egypt, 1990-1993, (2 folders) (Box 95)
      - General, 1987-1991, undated, (3 folders) (Box 95)
      - Gulf information, 1990-1991 (Box 96)
      - Hearings:
        - 1991 (Box 96)
        - Arab-Israeli, 1991 (Box 96)
        - Democratization, 1991 (Box 96)
        - Economic issues, 1991 (Box 96)
        - History/Culture/Religion (Box 96)
        - Middle East postwar, 1991-1992 (Box 96)
        - Role of U.N., 1991 (Box 96)
        - Security challenges, 1991 (Box 96)
        - Search for peace, 1991 (Box 96)
      - In Defense of Democracy article, 1991 (Box 96)
      - India, 1988-1992 (Box 96)
      - Iran:
        - 1987-1992 (Box 96)
        - Hostages, 1991 (Box 96)
      - Iraq, 1988-1992, (9 folders) (Box 96)
      - Israel, 1984-1992, undated, (9 folders) (Box 96)
      - Israel: (Box 97)
        - Palentine peace, 1991 (Box 97)
        - General, undated (Box 97)
        - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 97)
      - Jordan, 1988-1991 (Box 97)
      - Korea, undated (Box 97)
      - Kuwait, 1988-1992 (Box 97)
      - Kuwaitis in North Carolina, 1990-1991 (Box 97)
      - Lebanon, 1987-1991 (Box 97)
      - McCarthy- Tunisia, 1990-1991 (Box 97)
      - Middle East:
        - Hearings, 1991, (3 folders) (Box 97)
        - Lecture: Jimmy Carter letter, 1991 (Box 97)
        - Peace conference, 1991, (2 folders) (Box 97)
      - Nominations, 1992, (2 folders) (Box 97)
      - andldquo;October Surprise,andrdquo; 1991-1992, (2 folders) (Box 97)
      - Pakistan:
        - 1987-1992, (4 folders) (Box 97)
        - Nuclear, 1989-1991 (Box 97)
      - Peace, 1991 (Box 97)
      - Persian Gulf:
        - 1987-1991, (5 folders) (Box 97)
        - Condolences, 1991 (Box 98)
        - Hearings, 1990 (Box 98)
        - Pickering/ Baker hearing, 1990 (Box 98)
        - Sanford statements, 1990 (Box 98)
        - War, 1990-1991 (Box 98)
      - Press clips/bulletins, 1990-1991 (Box 98)
      - Sanford/ Iraq memorandum subject response to callers about Larry King Show, 1990, Aug.27 (Box 98)
      - Saudi Arabia, 1987-1988 (Box 98)
      - Saudi Arabian Standards Organization, 1987-1989 (Box 98)
      - Saudi Arms Sale, 1989-1992 (Box 98)
      - Search for Peace, 1991 (Box 98)
      - Sri Lanka, 1989-1992 (Box 98)
      - Syria, 1991 (Box 98)
      - Travel, 1991-1992 (Box 98)
      - United Arab Emirates, 1991 (Box 98)
      - United Nations, 1991 (Box 98)
    - Subcommittee on African Affairs, 1988-1991
      Reports, clippings, memoranda, and legislative proposals pertaining to United States policy towards South Africa.
      - South Africa: (Box 98)
        - 1988-1991, (6 folders) (Box 98)
        - Education project, 1990-1991 (Box 98)
    - Defense, 1986-1992
      Correspondence, committee and staff memoranda, reports, proposed treaties and legislation, and clippings. Issues addressed include the Persian Gulf War, defense budget appropriations and authorization bills, veterans affairs, weaponry programs, treaties, military bases, and women in combat.
      - Airborne Anniversary: 517th ICT, 1988-1989 (Box 99)
      - Airborne commemorative stamps, 1992 (Box 99)
      - Aircraft carrier procurement, 1986-1988 (Box 99)
      - Air Force: B-2, 1989-1990 (Box 99)
      - Air Force National Guard: Greensboro, 1987 (Box 99)
      - Air Force ROTC unit closings, 1986-1989 (Box 99)
      - Airspace:
        - Cherry Point, 1986-1989, (3 folders) (Box 99)
        - MAEWR-Mid Atlantic Electronic Warfare Range testing, 1986-1988, (2 folders) (Box 99)
        - Oak Grove: andldquo; Jones County, North Carolina,andrdquo; 1989, (2 folders) (Box 99)
        - Piney Island: USMC, BT-AA, 1988, Oct.25 (Box 99)
        - Seymour Johnson, 1984-1988 (Box 99)
        - Special Use Airspace, 1989-1990 (Box 99)
      - Arms control, 1987 (Box 99)